[Music]
oh did you think that i was working on
the interior for the mansion
um no
sorry
i was just pressing this button that
makes construction noises
i had you for a minute there didn't i
truth is i have been thinking about the
interior last episode i was wondering if
the mansion
could get bigger and the answer is yes
it could
but a lot of people basically said that
the mansion
really needed some interior
and
i get that it definitely does look at it
it is empty
messy
and a waste of potential the only thing
i've got going for me in here is a melon
and pumpkin farm so for now
we'll keep the construction button and
we'll leave that
until i could
magic string
until we can figure out what we're going
to do
with the entire place i have an idea i
just haven't figured out how to make it
work yet now in the chat a second ago
iskall was just saying that he couldn't
find any decked out keys and i started
feeling a little bit bad because i now
am sitting on four
decked out keys
so to give him the opportunity to get
one because he was looking for an hour
in the shopping district and they go
really really quickly
so i figure
i'll sell one decked out dungeon key and
give iskall the opportunity to buy it
from me
i guess it doesn't have to be much
this is basically me sharing
five diamonds they are pretty rare five
diamonds is a pretty good price
there we go i'll i'll basically just uh
i'll just put it in the chat that there
is one there bargain
you hear that bargain and while we're
here we might as well look at our sales
this was the
hold on we sold all okay i might have
undervalued these
massively rocket box for six diamonds
and they sold out in a day we got
diamonds out the wazoo and every single
mystery box is gone
including
the challenge box
wow these are really popular i know that
they're worth it they are worth all of
the diamonds that you pay
but i think i might mix it up every time
i do an iteration of this so we might
make
all challenge boxes now look at that
look at this it's all about getting
people to part with their shiny blue
rocks that's what hermitcraft is the
definition of hermitcraft i've i've
figured it out i've sussed it out
getting people to part with their
diamonds that is that is how you can sum
up this game 47 diamond blocks
absolutely insane i don't know how rich
the other hermits are but we are
definitely we've definitely got to be up
there with that
oh and right on schedule
i think someone wants a decked out key
it's it's here
it's hit what's going on with your
eyeball whoa
what do you see he's vanishing
what is going on
oh my god that scared the life out of me
oh no
you're welcome
you you scared me a bit
oh no
something
uh so something went wrong with my zoom
oh if you zoom in on his name he
vanishes
that is so weird
oh that is
[Laughter]
jumped out of my skin
and and breathe
and out
okay
uh that was that was a that was a good
deed we just did because i know that
iskal was looking for an hour in the
shopping district admittedly i was
looking for ages for a decked out box as
well
right so let's take a look at our
mycelium now people have bought some so
i'm not gonna keep paying myself to
enter i'm just gonna use the the back
door into the the resistance hq
surprisingly difficult to find oh there
there it is what have we got
yo
etho has decided i hope to join the
mycelium resistance oh idea rent
billboard for resistance recruitment
that's a pretty good idea slogan idea
spread the spores
mycelium the floors i like that i'm not
sure it'll fit on the billboard but
that's that's pretty good
i mean etho's a fun guy
fungi
mushrooms are we just are we the fun
guys is that it are we the fun guys
oh my goodness there's mushrooms oh he's
built an extra room in here
place to harvest mycelium yes
this is a really good idea
i did want to do this uh maybe we could
do a bit of a bigger room for this i
could extend this quite easily so you
just place down the dirt
and then harvest the mycelium afterwards
that's oh wow oh it spreads it spreads
quickly this is brilliant we can farm
this up
oh it's because there's mycelium above
it
so it only has one place it can go
which is downwards that's pretty smart i
mean the fun guys is a pretty good pun
but there are there's only so many
mushroom puns that you can use i think i
just thought of another one there's not
there's not much room in here is there
okay puns
puns hurt the soul i usually do them by
accident so i probably shouldn't even
try so with etho on board this is
actually pretty cool so i've been
thinking maybe
now we've got something to harvest the
mycelium with
what we could do
is
not enter the road building competition
see if you look here
all shops must pay for a road pass to
connect to the r rowed network
the rap available in the town hall
so there's a competition and it's being
judged you see but i think we could
we could silently enter
and create
the underground mushroom highway if
they're gonna ban us from all the roads
and access to our shops we're gonna make
our own access to people shops
it might take a little while but that
would be pretty cool i think creating a
little highway
underneath the shopping district
to each and every shop so i'm going to
go ahead and make like a prototype
style tunnel and we'll see what it looks
like transition check it out i have
created
at least a prototype of the tunnel that
i'm thinking of we've got plenty of
bricks and the reason that i've used
bricks is because i've got actually
quite a lot in the barge that aren't
being sold so i thought i might as well
put them to good use i think that's a
good height i like the way it's lit
overall i think it's quite cool but this
did take
well over an hour to make one section of
it
so i definitely need some more recruits
to help me
and we also need to figure out where
each shop is just by
digging around
so this is not a small project by any
means
so i'm gonna there's seems to be lots of
tunnel duty on hermitcraft at the moment
but i'm hoping i will get this done i
think this looks pretty cool and no one
has to know unless they're in the
resistance about this cool little
underground it literally does look like
the london underground the mycelium
highway i love it so
when i meet up with etho hopefully i can
show him the mycelium highway we can
build a little bit of this together and
i'm hoping that he will he will
volunteer to do the redstone
for this i don't know how this works i
don't know how rails intersect and stuff
but actually speaking of etho i messaged
him recently about the upside down
project it's something that's been put
off for a while now but i think it's
time we went and had a look at it but
before that i need to head back to my
base really quick because i need to pick
up a bunch of turtle eggs
that's how the the pigman farm works but
while i'm here
and while we're speaking of it this is
an etho heavy
episode today actually because last
episode
we saw this
ethos smells like and i asked you guys
in the comments what does etho smell
like and i've got to admit
they weren't the most original answers
in the world we got cheese
feet etho smells like etho
come on guys
but one comment did stick out that i
quite liked and it was etho
smells like
beef
etho
smells like
beef now this raises more questions than
it answers because now the question
isn't what does ethos smell like
the question is now
what does beef smell like so if anyone
knows what vintage beef smells like
that's what etho smells like as well by
the end of the season we're probably
going to end up with an essay about what
etho smells like so we've got our turtle
eggs now let's head over to the upside
down through the magic portal that is
the mansion
magic you say
watch this
magic teleport
and how do we do this through the power
of editing so since we're in the upside
down we have to wear our upside down
skin and it looks so wrong
don't talk to my feet talk to the face
so the plan is
to make a hole
right there not a huge huge hole but one
big enough
for us to have the zombie pigmen drop
straight down and into the fire
collection system
so
the hole actually needs to be around
here somewhere
now i've only just learned this
technique from impulse
so i don't actually know if it's gonna
work okay so from what i understand this
is the setup it's pretty simple very
basic materials you have to
flick this lever
oh you're meant to get under there then
you have to spam click
oh my goodness did i do it
no
okay
and then you have to right click this
did it work
yes okay that is amazing that is amazing
so now
only a bazillion more bedrock to go
so we might as well get started
[Music]
you know there are many heroes on the
hermitcraft server there are those that
keep us safe at night like bdubs and
there are those like impulse that save
us from hours of bedrock breaking and
i'm about to trigger everyone's ocd
really badly and there are things in my
videos that get on people's nerves and
i'm like ah does doesn't matter it's not
a big deal but this one yeah this one's
this one's gonna bother you it uh it
doesn't line up it doesn't line up at
all
the myth somehow i messed up really
badly at least this is in line with the
doorway but
i missed the middle
by a substantial amount but check it out
this was three hours believe it or not
of bedrock breaking because you have to
break
enough space to be able to move the
machine steadily downwards and without
impulse this would have been a nightmare
so i officially owe him some help on a
grind at some point but it means now we
can get started on
the pigman farm and we want to make as
many layers of this as possible repeat
this many times over and we have
ourselves a farm
so i mean this this is definitely
something that
i'm going to time lapse because
making
lots of magma layers is not particularly
fun to watch
[Music]
knock knock who's that
orange orange hay
weren't you glad i did the intro
i thought you honestly i thought you
were just gonna say knock knock who's
there etho what's up
what's up
welcome to the upside down uh we've
actually just had a conversation about
our plans but we figured we should
probably explain what we're gonna do
um so yeah that would be a great idea
welcome to the upside down mansion we've
decided that this is just going to
become a massively functional place and
we need all the help we can get to make
a good gold farm and then we can
trade with the piglens and then we can
all have access to the multiple blocks
that they produce i'm going to fall down
here drop their gold we're gonna collect
it we're gonna trade it with the piglens
we're gonna trade that with the stuff
and then everything's gonna be cool you
just clarify you've not made a gold farm
on hermitcraft right i have actually
yeah it's like wait
this is the second one you're making
i'm in the middle of making my own at my
own base what
i got another base too yeah i know
you're a madman well thank you for thank
you for helping i saw that you've uh
you've made a little base over there
which is cool it's not not exactly
upside down but you know i'll allow like
it's uh okay hey come over here for a
second what's the reason no no rules
board so i looked at this i thought for
sure rule number one would be
all builds have to be upside down oh no
i mean it's it's not a requirement it's
not a requirement um but i tell you what
we're all breaking number three at the
moment
uh yeah
come check out my place so great this is
cool it it's a lantern it's a full-size
lantern i actually really like the
design i'm not going to lie you just
look like you're wearing like a lot of
makeup on this your face wait how do you
get in
you gotta get in from the top like
you're filling it up with oil but you're
filling it up with green instead
you got the respawn anchor here
nice
nice and this is this is one of my
corners over here
it's my cozy corner this is my
productive corner
this is my thinking corner
and this is yours this is my visitor's
corner there's nothing
here nothing in here
this is a visitor's corner you have to
stand here all right sorry yeah
but thankfully we can leave this place
just by uh stepping on the trapdoor this
is this is the exit
yeah geronimo we're done we're done with
the tour already actually that's it i i
enjoyed it
okay so i think i think we're pretty
we're pretty clear on what we're gonna
do here right i'm gonna i'm gonna take
care of like the buildy stuff upstairs
with all the magnum blocks i will supply
the redstone stuff because i mean this
is gonna be a lot of blocks and then you
kind of take care of the technical stuff
and you can have access to as many
blocks as you like that the piglens
create that sound cool awesome that
sounds like a good deal friendship look
at them all tumble down
the rates on this thing aren't that
great but you can see that the pig the
zombie pigmen are wow actually it's it's
not bad at all
so i've got to say
a massive thank you to etho for helping
me not only get this part of the design
right but he started doing some of the
technical stuff down below as well now i
gotta say if you guys like minecraft
videos
and i know you do
if you guys like minecraft videos and i
know that you do i thoroughly recommend
checking out ethos videos they are
phenomenal i was hanging out with him
for a couple of hours while we were
working on this
and he's such a cool guy check this out
he's made a bunch of piglet tubes i
guess you'd call them so i guess it's my
job to get some piglins in here and then
ethos gonna fix up all the redstone for
it and you can see down here
we've got ourselves a few this is like i
don't know a few minutes of afk so we've
already got a bunch of golden blocks but
this place is definitely still a work in
progress
and hopefully we can get this looking
nice but hopefully b-dubs can come in
here and take out all of these extra
spawn locations that the pigs are taking
up and we can have this really producing
the stuff that we're gonna need but for
now let's head back actually i'm gonna
grab stuff turns out i've got loads of
shulker boxes full of stuff that can be
very useful
so i might as well take this back to the
base so now we're loaded up on shulker
boxes
let's head back
to the overworld where i actually want
to play a bit of decked out again don't
tell anyone i forgot about the upside
down skin i'm going to end up on tunnel
duty and sky's not even done his tunnel
duty yet what the heck no
no
why why is my portal come back on this
tree
i've got my decked out boxes and now we
descend
into the labyrinth
to spend them to recap here is my decked
out board and i got out with a little
bit not a huge amount but a little bit
so now we have three attempts
to get what we need these compasses are
now no longer used so all that matters
from these decked out boxes are the keys
and the coins and i acquired these all
from the shopping district but these
compasses are now null and void
according to tango
so we've got some free shulker boxes
which is cool so
one key in the dungeon enter the dungeon
you get your compass compass 79.
put everything
in the chest except for the compass i've
forgotten my loot finder card so i've
got an empty box i'm going in again
activate and we are going
in
let's try and let's try to get through
this fairly quickly
oh man
parkour
what
no
[Music]
yeah we okay we made it
oh is it
here
oh my goodness we got that very quickly
wait where did it go
i've been cheated
no
my book
my
my token
no
oh that's rotten that's absolutely
rotten
okay well there goes my loot but uh
maybe i can find some other things if i
quickly run around
oh that's a ravager we're leaving we're
leaving we don't want
him
that is some rotten luck
[Music]
there's a chest down there
how do you this is amazing
do i have to oh wow okay
i i kind of want to go down there but
i'm not entirely sure how i mean that's
amazing
[Music]
no he hit the thing ah okay i think we
call that one a dud and i won't get my
loot token
even though i probably i'll be honest
with you i probably would have just
taken that token and left
i only continued because
i didn't have anything to lose really
alright now we wait for the dungeon to
reset
there we go the doors have closed again
meaning we can put another key in
and we reset
we got our compass compass 75 we are
resetting our spawn here and we are
going again
this time we're getting in
we're getting our book and we're getting
out none of this messing around
submit
our cards which we don't have any of and
we go again
right it's this way
pretty sure this is
this is easily the direction of a
ravager
[Music]
whoa that was a booty of a ravager that
i just stuck my nose in
that scared the living daylights out of
me
that was a that was a very stupid move i
just made
there are many ravages where i need to
go i should have really eaten before i
came in
because now i can't sprint anywhere
here again
[Music]
okay
no ravages here
can i crouch under
[Music]
i hear
i hear my clank increasing i hear a
ravager
this is exactly where i was two seconds
ago
okay
guess where we're not going no
is he passing
no he saw me he saw me he saw me there's
nowhere for me to go
[Music]
okay we need to find another route
i don't know the dungeon layout enough
we need to somehow get
to this side of the dungeon
without hitting dead ends
[Music]
we can do this
what is going on here
oh
oh he's in the water
will i be okay if i just skedaddle i
reckon i'll be okay
we need to pay attention
[Music]
uh oh
uh
i think
i've
fallen into the machine
that's not somewhere you're supposed to
be
oh no i don't really know what to do
i can't get back up
hello
okay i've made her i've made it back in
but this is a bit unfair
if the rev
the doors are closed
time for round three
this time we've got ourselves a soul
seeker
i think that helps me find the soul
seeker flames got myself a compass 80
we are good to go
let's go
let's play this safe
i don't know what soul seeker does
exactly
now let's not fall in this take it nice
and easy
no
you're joking
have a nice day
we've had
three of the worst decked out runs
i think has ever been possible
you know what reuse that compass
i'm not gonna have a nice day tango if
you see what's what's happened here
today take pity on me
take pity okay so i messaged tango to
say what happened and he said yeah that
was a that was a mistake so he's gonna
pop over and give me two new keys which
is uh really nice he didn't have to do
that
i would have quite happily have taken my
dud runs i was a bit cheeky of me to
have three keys in the first place but
tango said no no no no gotta do it
properly so he's gonna hand me some keys
but that that last one that last one
we've we've got to take the the l on
that one that was just embarrassing
dad did i just see tango he's just
vanished
i promise not to waste them
get rabbit he doesn't want me to win
okay we're doing this we're doing this
we're going again
here we go
let's do it
i think i i see the admin now
checking everything's gonna be okay
oh do i really have to go this through
this again this has been the death of me
once already
come on
don't do this to me
[Music]
okay
ah
no
yes okay we made it
oh
any ravages
which way do i want to go
i think this way
i got sweaty hands this time
i feel like so much is riding on this
[Music]
okay
we need to be careful this time oh
was that ravager sense
i don't hear any ravages
speed is of the
utmost importance
this is a bit scary
oh man
my clank must be bad because all the
all the visibility doors are opening
i think it's down here no maybe it's
that way
come on
haven't got time oh
yes
yes yes loot box token
okay
do we take the way back that we know is
safe but dangerous
or
do we go back the way that has no lava
this is spooky
i think
i think we take the route
i think we go back the lava route
i think we get out of here with a loot
box token
oh the lag
[Music]
you can do this
is this jump that's the worst
oh my goodness that was the worst thing
ever
oh
oh my heart my little heart of my sweaty
hands we made it out
oh we made it out
oh my goodness
my little heart
we did it
we done diddly did it we got our box
back
and what did we get
resistance soul seeker
oh beast sense one let's take a beast
sense one shall we my goodness let's get
our stuff back
there we go
i think i'm done
i'm done for today loot box token in
here in you go hey we got a decked out
box
loot 35
we got a dragon set rare
shiny set common and nether set common
and some more decked out coins
so actually we've got two dragon set
rares we got another nether set and we
got a shiny
i think that's enough for today don't
you thank you very much for watching as
always and if you did enjoy the video
please consider subscribing it turns out
there's lots of you that watch that
aren't actually subscribed so i don't
know if actually asking you to subscribe
helps but it helps me out so thank you
very much for watching and i shall see
you in the next episode
good
bye
oh we nailed that look at that nailed it
you